GBD6 Astra is the most powerful AI model
I've ever used. So, I turned it into my
AI operating system and my second brain.
And this is just a quick visual, but
right now what you're seeing is my
actual company. This is my second brain.
This is everything that I know and
everything about my business. And
because I have everything actually
stored and usable, that means so does
GPT6 Astra. So when I say AIOS, what I
mean by that is an AI operating system
where now I can basically do anything I
need to from right inside of this
interface with Codeex with GPT6 Astra
because now it doesn't feel like I'm
just talking to a chatbot. It feels like
I'm talking to a co-founder, someone
that actually knows everything that's
going on in my life and my business. So
today I'm going to show you guys how you
set up an AI operating system from
scratch. But if you already have one
going, how you can keep improving it.
And I'm going to give away a bunch of
free skills that help you set up exactly
this and help you set up other things
like auditing your AIOS, leveling it up,
and just setting up the structure. Right
now, what you'll notice here is that
this isn't just a random dump of
knowledge. Right here in blue, this is
my business wiki. So, it's like AIS
coaching, our corporate structure, our
Ammation Society Plus. And when I click
in, we can see all of these things in
these different relationships. I can
also see how stale this is, so I might
need to update it. And it calls out all
these areas where like this number is
old. I need to update this. But it also
shows me all the different connections
where this specific node is linked into
every other area of my business. So like
I said, that was business wiki. I also
have meetings that I've added in here,
which takes up a big section. I've got
video knowledge. So every single YouTube
video I've made, it has all that
knowledge and it relates it back to
everything in my business and in my
meetings. Same thing with the clawed
memory right here as you can see. Same
thing with codeex memory. I've also got
a bunch of projects and then I have
skills and agents and this forms
together my herk brain. And I've even
gone as far as to take this exact brain
and put it in its own OS dashboard where
I can basically have my calendar over
here. Today's a Sunday so I don't have
many meetings. And this is fully
functional, fully synced with my
calendar. We've got these three stats,
YouTube subs, AIS, AIS Plus, and these
are fully synced. I can come in here and
manage my brain. I can search for
different things. I can look through
different things. I also have my
communication fully synced. So Slack,
ClickUp, and email, and these are
functional. I can respond to things from
here. I can also see different meetings
that I have coming up as well as past
meetings with the AI summaries already
generated. And then I can get community
pulse. So top YouTube comments, top AIS
plus posts, what people are stuck on, as
well as industry pulse from things like
YouTube and X. And all of this of course
was made with GBT6 Astra. But really the
idea of an AIO OS or an operating system
is my framework that I call the four
C's. So context, connections,
capabilities, and cadence. And the way
that I think about this is I think about
these first two things as the second
brain piece. So I think of this as your
second brain. And then over here we have
the actual AIOS and this is the
capabilities and the cadence. So, let me
real quick explain what I mean by that.
What's the actual difference? So, the
way that you get this thing to actually
feel like it knows you is by giving it
context. So, I mean things about you and
your background and your business and
your goals and your priorities and
things like that. I think of context as
the things that are in your life that
really don't change too much. So,
quarterly goals or yearly goals or what
your business does, your avatar, pain
points, things like that. And the
connections, I think of things as the
tools that you use every day because the
data in there is always relevant and
it's always changing every day. So, your
email, different data is always in
there. Your conversation, Slack,
ClickUp, your project management, your
financial information, giving your AOS
the ability to know all the context, but
also reach for things just in time when
it needs it. That's how you build a
really, really powerful second brain
that helps you actually ask your AIOS
questions or say something. And rather
than getting a vague or generic
response, it knows what to do. So, for
example, when I asked Codex to make me
this AIS sizzle reel, I didn't tell it
everything I wanted. I just said, "Hey,
make me a sizzle reel for AI Automation
Society." And it knew all this context.
And it also knew that it could go to my
school community and look things up in
order to make this. In fact, what you'll
notice is it actually went so far as to
go to the community, take pictures from
it, like take screenshots itself and add
those in here because it knew that this
is what I was talking about. So, I have
these three little tests that I like to
run, which is basically if a teammate
messages you with a question and you
realize that your AIOS would answer
better and faster with the exact
sources, then that's a good sign that
your AIOS really is where it should be.
Another one is context switching
reduction. One thing that you should
challenge yourself to do after you've
gotten this set up is to try to force
yourself to do everything from here from
this interface. Rather than opening up
all those new tabs and doing it the old
way, try doing it the new way of using
the AI as your operating system. And
then number three is the knowledge
leaves your head. So stop trying to
remember everything. You don't have to
rehearse what you decided last quarter
or what your customer said in that
meeting because you trust the retrieval
of asking your AIOS because it can find
it in your Slack threads. it can find it
in your email, find it in your meetings,
or it just knows it. Because if you
start to build new skills and
capabilities, and you start to put
cadence into play, which means agents
that run autonomously and automations
and things like that, these things are
not nearly as valuable without the first
two C's because otherwise these skills
are very generic. And automations are
just like I said, generic. So these four
things really come one after the other,
context, connections, capabilities, and
cadence. And they all work together very
beautifully. And that's how we get our
AI operating system. So, in order to get
started or to scale all this up and get
all the resources, I need you to go to
my free school community. The link for
that is down in the description. Like I
said, it's completely free. And you're
going to go to classroom. You're going
to click on all YouTube resources. And
you're going to grab the AISOS resource
pack. This thing is going to come with
five skills. It'll come with an onboard
skill to get you set up. It'll set up
your whole project structure, your
files, and your folders. Then, you'll
have an audit skill to do frequent
checks on your AOS. You'll have a link
skill, which helps you route to
different files when you need to. You'll
have a level up which you can run after
your audits that tell you, hey, this is
probably some stuff you should do based
on this audit. And then you have the 3D
brain skill which helps you turn your
knowledge into this actual 3D brain like
you guys saw right over here. Now, yes,
it is these four things. And when you
start to run that resource pack, it'll
onboard you and ask you questions and it
will start to fill in this information
which is great. But then what comes next
is something that's super super
important and that is called the
agents.md.
And so if you've been using Claude, this
is basically the claw. MD, but now this
is the one that CodeEx is more familiar
with reading and it's the exact same
thing. So if you are coming over from
Codeex, literally what I would do is I
would just copy your claw.md and then
just name it agents.mmd. It's the exact
same thing. And just to show you guys
what mine looks like, if I go into here
and I go to my files, you can see that
it's very simple. It's you are Nate
Herki operating system. Here's your job.
Agents.mmd and cloud.mmd contain the
same stuff. And then I basically give it
a few core operating rules like to be
concise and I use bullet points and
don't use m dashes and you know use the
Oxford comma. But then I go into a
routing map and that's the majority of
my agents.mmd. I think of it as you know
core rules but then I think of it as
routing meaning can my agent understand
where everything lives because if I open
up my herk 2 project which is just like
we said a combination of folders and
files and that's all this is displaying
is folders and files and it's showing
the relationship between all of that.
But the point I'm trying to make is that
this is a lot right? There's a lot of
folders and files and I can go into my
projects and there's a lot more in here
and then I can go into things like, you
know, my YouTube videos in here and it's
even more. But because all of this is
laid out in a way that to me is
intuitive, that also means that my
agents can crawl it a little bit better.
But the more that I have information in
here like routing logic, like, hey, if
you need business advice or team stuff
or OTAAS, you look in the wiki. If you
need corporate structure or entities,
you look in this section of the wiki. If
you want to look at Nate's voice and
style, you look here. If you want to
look at course knowledge, you look here.
If you want to look X, go Y. If you want
to look A, go B. And you can see there's
a ton of different rules in here. But
what's important is that the agent knows
this every single time it loads up so
that when you ask for something, it
knows where to look because that's
essentially how the agents.mmd file
works. You know, you say, "Hi, codeex."
And before it even will read your
message, it reads this first. So it
reads this and then it reads your
message and then it will respond with
like, "Hey, how can I help you today?"
You know, that's kind of what it will
say. But it always reads this context
first, which is why it's so important.
All right, so if you're a complete
beginner, how do you actually get set up
with all this? Well, let me show you.
First thing, what you're going to want
to do is you're going to want to go to
somewhere on your computer. Let's just
say it's your desktop. And you're going
to create a new folder. And so, for
example, this is where I am using my
Herk 2 project. But for now, I'm just
going to call this AISOS
demo. So, you can call this whatever you
want. Now, once that folder has been
created locally, which just means on
your computer, you're going to open that
up in Codeex. So, at this point, if you
don't have the Codeex desktop app,
download that. And then if you aren't on
a subscription, just get on
subscription. But now what we're going
to do is we need to open up this OS. So
what that means is you would come in
here and you would click on new project.
You would create a local project and
then you would give it a name and then
choose this folder. So this is once
again going to be AIS demo and I'm going
to open up that folder. If I go to my
desktop and I just have to find this
folder we just made right here. Select
that and then go ahead and click create
project. So this now means whenever we
are doing things in here, we're working
inside of this actual local folder,
which if I open this up, there's nothing
in here right now. But you will see as
we start this whole onboarding, this
folder will fill up. So what I'm going
to do is I'm going to go to the resource
pack and I'm just going to copy this
actual URL. And I will now paste that
into the chat and say, hey, I want you
to install this and just go ahead and
run the onboard so I can start giving
you some information and building my
AIOS. So now that this is installed,
it's going to start onboarding you. And
you can see that it's going to say, "I
will save your answer as you go." So,
obviously, you guys should take some
time and give this some pretty specific
information, but I'm just going to blow
through this real quick. So, my name is
Nate and I run an AI education community
and we have a certification program and
we have live events and things like
that. And what's going to happen is it's
going to start creating folders and
files for you. If you click on this
button and you go to files, you can see
that it's already created a bunch of
stuff in here. None of this was in here.
If you guys remember, this was all
completely empty, but now it's starting
to set up the actual structure. But
really the two most important things to
call out right now are the context
folder. This is where it's going to
start to create some markdown files of
business context and also the
agents.mmd. I remember I showed you guys
mine and this is going to start getting
built out over time with you guys right
in here. Then it asks you to paste some
of your recent writing so that it can
start to build some skills around how
you write. So what I'm going to do real
quick is just basically fly through
these seven questions and then you guys
do this as well and then come back. All
right. So now that I've done those seven
questions, if I open up a new thread, I
can actually say, "Hi, who am I?" and it
will check my profile first because now
it can actually look at all that and
understand that. So if I open up the
files once again, we can now see that if
I go to my context, we have one called
about business, we have one called about
me, and we have one called priorities.
So if I open this up, you can see that
this has information. If I open this one
up, this one has information, too. And
over time, these will continuously get
more filled with context. And this is
context, like I said earlier when I was
talking about these four C's, context
that we want to basically be more
evergreen, right? information that's not
changing very often. Whereas these are
more the connections where you have
information that changes very often. And
that's when you're going to start
filling it up by looking at things like
this. You're going to start looking at
um what bookmarks do you have, what
desktop apps do you have, what apps do
you use the most on the weekly basis.
And I like to think about it as far as
like revenue, customers, calendar,
comms, tasks, meetings, and knowledge.
And then once you've taken some time to
like list them out here, just say, "Hey,
Codeex, I want to connect to school. how
can I do that? I want to connect to
Stripe. I want to connect to YouTube.
How can I do that? And it will tell you,
oh, you need to get this API key or you
need to use this MCP server or maybe you
need to use browser use. And it will
help you figure out the best way to
connect to all these tools. But what
else you'll notice is that it's creating
the things that we need in case you ever
want to go over to cloud code like
acloud folder as well as a cloud.mmd. So
it's really helping you make this your
own AIOS, your own IP where you're not
locked into one ecosystem. So anyways, I
just wanted to call that out. But the
agents and the cloudmd file are
basically identical. Right now we have
like the operating system, we have some
skills, we have where things live, but
right now this is pretty empty. So
obviously we need to get this filled up
a little bit more. You can also see that
in the references section we have a
voice. So if I go to my references and I
go to the voice MD, we can see that this
is stuff about how Nate talks based on
the information that I've given it so
far. So anyways, now you can see we're
starting to get some stuff filled up
here. But now what you'll do is once you
have connected some things, you're going
to go ahead and run the audit. So you
can do / audit. This will automatically
be installed because you used the
resource guide. And this basically
checks the AIOS. It looks at the four
C's. It gives you a score. And it will
also look at your agents MD or your
cloud NMD and make sure everything's
synced up like I said. And what else is
cool about this is this creates another
folder in your AIOS called audits. You
can see there's nothing here called
audits. But what's going to happen is
it's going to give you a report and then
it's going to store your audit. So every
single time you run this, let's say you
want to run it every Monday or every two
weeks, it will store your scores every
time so that you can see how you're
actually improving your system, you
know, month over month. So I know if
you're new to Codeex and everything,
this might feel a little bit
intimidating, but it's really not too
bad. And the cool thing about this is
you can just ask questions if you ever
get confused. Hey, why'd you do that? Or
where should I put this? Or, you know,
how do you feel about all this? You can
treat this thing like your best friend
who's really smart, who's also a mentor
rather than just like a chatbot. Okay,
but you can now see that this audit is
done. And obviously, we scored a 30 out
of 100 because we literally just built
this and there's not much in here. But
it'll show you across those four C's
what needs improvement. And you can keep
working on that stuff. And over here,
you can see that we have a new folder
called audits. We have this markdown
file which shows us that today,
September 7th, you ran this audit. And
here was basically the conclusion of
that audit so that you can improve on
it. Now, what you can do from there is
you can go ahead and run another skill
which comes in the kit which is called a
level up. So, this one will basically
look at this audit report and then it
will help suggest areas for you to
improve it. It'll help you think about
different connections and different ways
that you could, you know, build in some
more capability and build in some more
cadence so that this thing keeps growing
and keeps growing. So, here you can see
it said, I'd start with turning team
updates into one clear action list. It
targets your stated bottleneck
coordination, taking time away from
learning AI and making videos. So, two
candidates here, which are team action
list and certification improvement
backlog. So, I would then think, okay,
cool. So how do we actually start
driving towards this? You know, what do
you need to see? What connections do we
need to set up? And then how do we build
these automations?
And so you can just keep running this
loop of auditing, leveling up, building,
auditing, leveling up, building. And
this is the type of stuff that Astra is
so good at because it's so so smart. It
really feels like it's got some really
incredible general intelligence,
especially as you give it more and more
data because it's really good at
building automations. It can oneshot a
lot of this stuff and it will help you
build all these routines. So automating
some of these little tasks is no
problem. The real issue is getting
everything from your head into the
system because the more you give it, the
more context you give it, the better it
gets obviously. So yes, it can give you
these recommendations, but now what I
want you guys to think about is how you
can give it more data. So I do have this
other skill here called Grill Me. It was
inspired by Matt PCO's Grill Me and I
will actually put this in the AIS OS
kit. So if you install it based on this
video, you'll have this here. But I
didn't do it right now. So anyways, then
you could use the grill me and say, I
need you to use this grill me skill to
just, you know, find out as much as you
can about my current priorities in my
business. And what this does is it will
basically do similar to the onboard
where it asks you questions, but this is
a separate skill where it just
relentlessly grills you over and over.
And what's cool about this is you just
keep having it grill you on different
topics because every time you start one
of these interviews, it will create a
new file in your AISOs and it will store
all this interview. So every single time
that you come in here for 20 minutes, 30
minutes, and you just get interviewed by
AI, it's going to store all that. So
you're just building up your second
brain over time, and it's really, really
cool. As you can see, it said, I'm going
to save every answer in business
priorities capture. It created a new
folder right here. And now we have this
markdown file where as I start to answer
these questions, it's going to store
everything. So that's something that I
would recommend going through with
business priorities, your team, you
know, your goals, and just like a bunch
of different topics about your business
and about your life. Now, the next thing
you need to do, and it's how you
actually get something more like this
where you actually have like all of
these relationships forming between
these different things that you want to
put into your AISOs or into your second
brain. This gets really important
because the relationships is what makes
this actually connect to everything and
what makes it feel more holistic rather
than just like a data dump. So, the way
that you get to this point with all
these relationships is we're going to
use Carpathy's LLM wiki. This basically
just has AI crawl through data sources
and find those connections for you. So,
it's really, really cool. And guess
what? It's really easy to use because
all you have to do is you can either
copy this URL, which I'll put in the
description of this video. Or you could
just come in here and you could copy
this. Like you could literally just go
like this, copy it, and then come into
your actual AISOs. You can start a new
chat and then say, "Hey, based on what
you currently know about me, I want you
to build me a new LLM wiki, and I want
you to do so on all my business contacts
and everything using this Carpathy wiki
method." And then you can literally just
paste in that prompt, and boom, it's
going to crawl through everything. It's
going to create you a new wiki vault.
And you can obviously be more specific
like I have one vault for my YouTube
videos. I have one vault for my business
knowledge. I have one vault for my
meeting transcripts. And so I started to
separate them out over time. But just to
start, you could do, hey, this one's
just for business or whatever you need
to do. And it will help you find those
relationships. And then once you've done
a bunch of grillies, once you've built
out these L&M wikis, then you're going
to go in here and you're going to run
that 3D brain skill. And that is the one
that's going to take all your knowledge
and it's going to turn it into something
like this. And this obviously will
continue to sync and stay optimized and
continue to improve for you. And it will
probably build that out into something
called a local host. But what's really
cool is you could ask it to turn that
into a site. As you can see, Codex
basically lets you build things and
store it on their domain. So then after
you build it, you could have it be
accessible to different laptops or to
your phone or whatever you want. Or if
you wanted to keep it local, you can do
that as well. And if you also wanted to
connect your own custom domain, you can
do that, too. So really, the
possibilities here are endless. And it's
just about doing that loop, like I said,
of constantly scaling up your four C's
and doing that loop of the audit level
up, audit level up. Now, the last thing
I wanted to address was the whole idea
of GBD6 Astra driving everything, right?
Because Astra is an incredibly powerful
model, but I also wanted to say so is
5.6 Soul and so is 5.6 Terra. And for
the majority of this knowledge work that
you're doing here in your AOS, like
asking, oh, can you find this doc or can
you help me create this spreadsheet? A
lot of that using Astra is probably
overkill. Like Astra is one of the most
it is the most capable model that I've
ever played with. So what I would
recommend is build out some of the
stuff. You know, get familiar with how
this model works. But then when you
start to try to, you know, use different
skills and when you start to try to
connect to different things, I would
recommend trying with 5.6 Soul because
Astro is going to crawl through your
usage limit, which is the weekly limit.
It's going to eat at that more because
it's a more expensive model than 5.6
Soul is. And once you really start to
get comfortable here, you can play with
different things too, like the effort
level. You can make it go on lights,
which reduces some of the capability,
but it also makes it cheaper. And then
you could also go to 5.6 soul, and you
could play with the effort level over
here as well. There's a lot of cool
things to dig into once you really start
to connect a lot of stuff to your codeex
system. Once again, I just think it's
important to call out that all you're
building here is you're building files
and folders. And what's cool about that
is as you build out your files and
folders, it will grow into something
that's just amazing. So now I have my
herk 2 which like I said has everything
in here. And the cool thing is if I
wanted to build a Hermes agent I can
connect that to this. If I go back to
cloud code I connect it to this.
Whatever is the new tool, whatever is
the new AI model, I don't have to worry
about switching over. I don't have to
worry about being vendor locked because
I own all of this stuff right here and
every agent can crawl through it and use
it. And that's really what we're
building here. We're not just building a
codec skill or a codeex hub or a little
like 3D brain. We're building IP. We are
building a knowledge base that is going
to be the most valuable thing because
now we can work through it because
there's so much context and knowledge in
here. So I really want you guys to
seriously get in there and start doing a
bunch of grill me and just building up
your routing and your context. So
remember free school community linked in
the description. You'll find all the
resources that you need right in here.
But that is going to do it for this one.
And if you guys now want to see since
you have an AIOS set up, how you can
control everything with your voice and
just delegate out tasks to a bunch of
different agents at the same time just
with your voice, then check out this
video which I'll tag right up here. I
hope to see you guys over there. Check
it out. It's super cool. And I'll see
you in the next one. Thanks everyone.